（マルチネ）
使命を果たすのです アーミラ
Fulfill your mission, Amira.
Do so, and your wish will surely come true.
そうすれば あなたの願いは
きっと かなうでしょう
In the promised land of Helheim.
約束の地“ヘルヘイム”で
Mother...
（アーミラ）
おかあ… さん
Hey, Amira! Pull yourself together!
（ファバロ）
おい アーミラ！　しっかりしろ！
Lady Amira!
（カイザル）
アーミラ嬢！
Take me...
（アーミラ）
つ… れて…
あ？　何だって？
Huh? What was that?
いって… いてて！
Take me to Helheim...
（アーミラ）
連れてって…
ヘル… ヘイムに… 早く
Quickly...
早く…
Quickly!
そうしてやりてえところだが…
I'd love to, but...
It's just one disaster after another now.
一難去って また 一難ってやつか
I'm waiting for sunrises again
Rise up, rise up, rise up
Let me see the sun
Rage of Bahamut
People always say
"black or white," but the world is so gray
Even angels and demons were once the son of God I praised
temee no gen'in wa temee no naka kara
You're the catalyst for your own demise
zenbu hikurumete omae no saga
It's inherent to your being
kizuku koro ni wa mou you're in a coffin
But by the time you realize, you're in a coffin
It's too late if you want to do something
What the hell is wrong with me?
I can't remember what I wanted to be
Tick, tack, which is what I found
I can see the keys are scattered around
kono yoru ga aketemo nanika kawaru wake ja nee sa
Even though a new day dawns, nothing's gonna change
Yes, I know; yes, I know that I...
I'm the only one
who can save myself
I'll never forget
All I wanna be is me
Gaurin, I don't see Lavalley.
（ジャンヌ）
ゴラン
ラヴァレイの姿が見えぬが
He left the rank earlier to check something.
（ゴラン）
先ほど 何か確かめることがあると
隊列を離れました
Check something?
確かめること？
Why is your wristband gone, Favaro?
（カイザル）
ファバロ
貴様 腕輪は どうした？
Whoa! When did that happen?!
（ファバロ）
あれ？　いつの間に
He destroyed it himself to save you guys.
（リタ）
自分で壊したのよ
あんたたちを助けるために
How about you keep your big mouth shut?
余計なこと言ってんじゃねえぞ
Isn't he your father's murderer?
こいつ 父親の敵(かたき)なんでしょ？
（ファバロの口笛）
とっとと殺(や)っちゃいなさいよ
Just kill him already!
I haven't a sword.
（カイザル）
剣がない
Then choke him to death!
（リタ）
なら 絞め殺したら？
I'm a knight.
（カイザル）
私は騎士だ
それに…
Besides...
We made an agreement.
約束… したからな
フン
Agreement?
（リタ）
約束？
（ファバロ）
さあてね
Anyway...
（リタ）
それにしても
なんで ヘルヘイムなの？
Why Helheim, though?
I hear it's uninhabitable and covered entirely in ice.
あそこは誰も住めない
一面 氷に閉ざされた場所だって
聞いてるけど
It's where her mom is, apparently.
そこに行けば会えるんだとさ
母ちゃんに
Cocytus
-------------------------------- The Demon Capital --------------------------------
（マルチネ）
そこで何を？
What have we here?
Martinet!
マルチネ…
Do you intend to meet with Lord Lucifer, Azazel?
（マルチネ）
ルシフェル様に
会うおつもりですか？
アザゼルぅ～？
貴様には関係のない話だ
It's none of your concern.
I'm amazed you had the gall to waltz back here after being caught off guard by mere humans.
人間ごときに不意打ちを食らい
よく
のこのこ戻ってこられましたね
Lord Lucifer would never agree to meet with such a fool.
そのような愚か者に
ルシフェル様は
お会いになりますまい
You're a loser, woof!
（オス犬）
負け犬がいるワン
（メス犬）
とっとと帰れワン
Get lost, woof!
You've already been filled in, I see.
（アザゼル）
なるほど… 手回しのいいことだ
In that case, I will go...
ならば 奪い返してこよう
and take back the God Key.
“神の鍵”をな
Anatae
-------------------------------- The Royal Capital --------------------------------
シャリオス13世 国王陛下に
最敬礼！
All bow to His Majesty, King Charioce XIII!
Jeanne D'Arc, maiden blessed by the gods,
（シャリオス）
ジャンヌ･ダルク
神に祝福されし乙女よ
you have accomplished yet another
magnificent feat. I am truly proud of you.
またしても見事な働き
お前を心から誇りに思う
I am grateful for your words.
（ジャンヌ）
ありがたきお言葉
Bring the prisoners here!
（ラヴァレイ）
捕らえた者たちを ここへ
（ファバロ）
いでっ！
あれが国王？
That's the king?
（ラヴァレイ）
国王陛下の前である　控えろ
Silence! You're in His Majesty's presence!
She is the one.
この者にございます
ふむ 見たところ 普通の娘にしか…
She looks like an ordinary girl to me.
Gems used to detect demons don't react to her, either.
（ジャンヌ）
確かに
魔族を見分ける法石にも
反応はありません
（シャリオス）
ふうむ…
（ミカエル）
それこそが
鍵を奪われた理由なのだ
Yet that is precisely why the key was stolen!
Th-Three angels descending at once?!
（シャリオス）
さ… 三天使様が
そろって降臨なさるとは
Oh, man. Get a load of these fancy gods.
おいおい
随分と派手な神様たちだな
バッカスとは大違いだ
They're nothing like Bacchus.
（バッカス）ぐごお～
（ハンサ）くわっ！
Even we angels were deceived by this girl.
（ミカエル）
だまされたのだ
我ら天使までもが その娘に
For that is her ability—
（ミカエル）
それこそが この娘の能力
the forbidden power to freely transform between angel and demon.
天使と悪魔の双方
自在に変化することのできる
禁忌の力
Lady Amira... is an angel?!
アーミラ嬢が… 天使？
いや 悪魔だろ！
No, a demon!
She's both.
どっちもよ
The fact that the key is now
within a demon, even if only half,
（ウリエル）
半身とはいえ
魔の者の中に鍵が取り込まれた以上
アークへ連れ戻すことはできぬ
means we cannot return it to the Ark.
King, you will keep her within Anatae under heavy guard.
（ラファエル）
王よ
娘を この王都アナティで
厳重に確保せよ
Of course!
（シャリオス）
ははあ！
I shall guard her with my life!
この身に代えましても 必ずや
Incidentally...
ところで…
What should be done about them?
あの者たちの処遇は いかに？
Why, they should be put to death, of course!
いや お尋ねするまでもなく
死罪でしょうが…
し… 死罪！
P-Put to death?!
It's all over.
（ファバロ）
終わった…
ほんの軽い気持ちでついたうそが
I can't believe that simple lie
wound up haunting me like this!
まさか
ここまで俺を追い詰めるとは…
You must not take their lives.
（ミカエル）
命を奪ってはならぬ
As you wish.
かしこまりました
Prepare to have them executed immediately...
では 早速 この者たちの処刑を…
Wait, what?
今 何と？
They will all remain in this city under your protection!
（ミカエル）
その者たち４人全員
この都にとどめ
護(まも)るのだ
Our protection?
（ジャンヌ）
護る？
You're an angel, all right! You're so understanding!
（ファバロ）
さっすが天使様！　話が分かる！
Behold!
（ミカエル）
見よ！
Wh-What is this?!
こっ これは…
The signs of Bahamut's revival grow ever more intense.
（ミカエル）
バハムート復活の予兆は
確実に激しさを増している
バハ… ムート？
Bahamut?
But it cannot yet wake.
（ラファエル）
だが まだ目覚めることはできぬ
To do so, it requires the two Transcendent Keys
最高神ゼウスと魔王サタンによって
生み出された２つの鍵…
created by the Supreme God Zeus and the Demon Lord Satan.
“神魔(しんま)の鍵”が
ヤツには必要なのだ
Should the Transcendent Keys become one with Bahamut,
（ウリエル）
もし 神魔の鍵が
バハムートと
ひとつとなるときあらば
horrendous catastrophes will befall all of creation
恐るべき厄災が天地に降りかかり
and the world will be pushed to the brink of destruction once more.
世界は再び
滅亡の危機に陥るであろう
Thus, it is unwise to end their lives.
いかなる影響を及ぼすか
分からぬかぎり
The ensuing emotional strain on the girl
could result in unforeseen consequences.
その者たちを殺(あや)め
娘の心に負担を課すのは
得策ではない
We must prevent Bahamut's revival at all costs.
バハムートの復活は
何としても阻止せねばならぬ
勇猛なる者たちよ
神の鍵を護るのだ
Keep the God Key safe, O valiant ones!
Of course!
（シャリオス）
ははあ！
What are you doing?! Release them at once!
何をしておる！
早く拘束を解かんか！
Yes, Sire!
Freedom is now yours as long as you remain in the city.
さあ この都にいるかぎりは自由だ
存分に旅の疲れを癒やすがいい…
May you soothe the weariness of your travels!
（ゴラン）
なっ… 貴様！
You cur!
Thank you, most merciful king!
ありがとうございます！
慈悲深き国王様…
あ… ありがとうございます！
Th-Thank you!
（シャリオス）オ… オホホホ…
（ファバロ）国王様 万歳！
Long live the king!
I hate this place!
（アーミラ）
こんなとこ やだ！
I want to go to Helheim!
ヘルヘイムに行く！
I want to go to Helheim and see my mother!
ヘルヘイムで お母さんに会う！
（ファバロ）
むちゃ言うなって！
Are you crazy?! You're in no condition to go anywhere!
そんなボロボロの体で
行けるわけねえだろうが
You promised you'd take me to Helheim!
君 約束した
ヘルヘイムに連れてくって！
W-Well, uh...
そっ それは…
You promised! You promised! You promised!
約束した！　約束した！
約束した～！
約束したさ！
Yeah, I did!
But only 'cause you put this curse on me!
でも それは…
お前が
こんな呪いをかけたからだ！
Huh? Is that...
おっ？　それは…
Wow, it's almost like he's a demon.
驚いた
まるで悪魔みたい
"Almost like"?
“まるで”？
He was cursed. He just said so himself.
（リタ）
今 言ったでしょ 本人が
“呪いをかけられた”って
He's a genuine, ordinary human.
この男は正真正銘 ただの人間よ
Favaro... is human?
ファバロが… 人間？
Well, duh! Of course I'm human!
当たり前だろ！　俺は人間だ！
So I ain't going to no Helheim!
だから
ヘルヘイムなんてとこには行かねえ
I'm not gonna keep risking my neck no more!
これ以上 危険な目に遭うのは
まっぴら御免だ！
So if you wanna go, then go by yourself!
どうしても行きてえんなら
お前１人で行け
ただし！
Just get this damn tail off me right this minute!
この クソいまいましい尻尾は取れ
今すぐに！
ぶはあ！
You liar!
うそつき！
Ow, my neck...
うお～ 首にきたあ…
Fiores Mondo Malit.
She can't leave the room now.
これで 部屋からは出られん
We'll watch her here until she has healed.
女は傷が癒えるまで
この部屋で監視する
The rest of you can use the room next door.
お前たちは隣の部屋を使え
I'd prefer a room to myself too, actually.
私も個室のほうがいいんだけど
（ゴラン）
いい気になるな
本来なら絞首刑だったものを
Don't push your luck.
You would've been hanged under any other circumstances.
Also, we must confiscate your weapons while you're inside the castle.
それから
城内にいる間は武器も没収だ
Damn.
What's that ringing?
（リタ）
何？　この鐘の音
警報だ
It's a warning bell.
魔族が現れた！
Demons have appeared!
Ghouls...
（ジャンヌ）
グールか
They're much larger than before, as well.
（ラヴァレイ）
以前に比べ
大きさも増しております
Then I'll simply eradicate them with this spear from the gods—the Maltet.
（ジャンヌ）
ならば 神より賜りし この槍
マルテで殲滅(せんめつ)するのみ
I feel it is unwise to go into battle alone, however.
（ゴラン）
しかし たったお一人だけで
出陣なさるのは…
No.
（ジャンヌ）
いや…
I can hear the voices of the gods, loud and clear.
はっきり聞こえるのだ
神の御言葉(みことば)が
迷わず薙(な)ぎ払えと！
They tell me to eliminate them at once!
It took out just the monsters.
化け物だけ斬りやがった
Her power continues to grow ever greater, I see.
聖女のお力
ますます さえ渡っていきますな
Perhaps it's because of the God Key.
（ラヴァレイ）
神の鍵の影響か…
This is almost unbelievable.
まさか ここまでとは
Demonkind is no match for us now!
もはや 魔族は敵ではない！
We have the blessings of the gods!
神の御加護(ごかご)は我らにあり！
The chosen maiden of the gods, huh?
神に選ばれし乙女か…
So, we've managed to contain Bahamut for now?
（ラファエル）
ひとまず
バハムートを抑えることはできたか
やはり 封印の維持に
鍵の娘の安寧は欠かせないようだな
It seems the key girl's well-being is
indeed vital to maintaining the seal.
Still, we can't afford to leave the key in the humans' custody forever.
しかし 鍵を いつまでも人間たちに
預けておくわけにはいかないね
The human Jeanne D'Arc was chosen to serve as a vessel.
（ラファエル）
本来 人間であるジャンヌ･ダルクを
依代(よりしろ)として見初めたはず
あの半身半魔に
奪われたままとあっては
You'll have a grave price to pay if that half angel, half demon keeps it from us, Michael.
君の責任は重いぞ
ミカエル
あのとき…
When it happened...
She was protected by a powerful magic being. I believe it was...
（ミカエル）
あの娘は強い魔力に護られていた
恐らく…
The one scheming to steal the key and lift Bahamut's seal.
（ガブリエル）
鍵を奪い バハムートの封印を
解こうと もくろむ者
I've received word from the knights.
（ミカエル）
騎士団より報告が
The key girl was on her way to Helheim, it seems.
鍵の娘は
ヘルヘイムを目指していたと
The location of the other key. Just as suspected.
（ガブリエル）
やはり もう１つの鍵は その地に
What shall we do?
（ミカエル）
いかがいたしますか？
娘を王都アナティに
とどまらせておくかぎり
The schemer will try something if we keep the girl in the Royal Capital of Anatae.
必ずや動きがあるはず
This is the perfect opportunity to find out who it is.
謀略者をあぶり出す良い機会です
Let us use the girl to our advantage.
利用させてもらいましょう
あの娘を
This is the life!
（ファバロ）
いや 最高！
I expected hell...
地獄かと思ったら…
ぷは～！
but wound up in heaven instead!
天国に来ちまった気分だなあ おい
ハッハッハ…
Are you sure this is the time for having fun and drinks?
（リタ）
いいの？
のんきに お酒なんか飲んでて
What happened to settling the score with him?
決着つけるんじゃなかったの？
ハア…
（カイザル）
リタ？
Rita?
This is boring. I'm going to bed.
（リタ）
退屈だから 部屋に戻って寝るわ
And every town I go to is just brimming with danger and beautiful women!
でな 俺が今まで渡り歩いた町は
常に危険と美女が いっぱいでな！
Oh, you!
（女Ａ）
やだ もう
What's the most dangerous place you've been to?
（女Ｂ）
ねえ
いちばん危険だった場所は どこ？
That would be...
（ファバロ）
それは…
I forget.
忘れちまった
Whoa, what's this?
で… なに これ？
Poor thing.
（男）
かわいそうに
Both mind and body, tortured so much.
（男）
身も心も そんなに傷つけられて
Who are you?
（アーミラ）
誰？
You wish to know the real reason you were born into this world, don't you?
（男）
お前は知りたいのだろう？
自分が この世界に生まれてきた
本当の理由を
I can grant you that wish.
私が その望みを かなえよう
Wait!
（アーミラ）
待って！
Oh, man.
もう ダメだ…
I'm never gonna drink again.
もう 飲めね～
（ファバロ）
なぜ ためらう？
What are you waiting for?
This is the perfect opportunity for you to get revenge.
恨みを晴らす
絶好のチャンスじゃねえか
I'm not sure anymore.
分からなく… なった
I don't know what's true or what I should do anymore.
（カイザル）
一体 何が本当なのか
私は何をすべきなのか
それが分からなくなったのだ
I don't know what to make of anything.
Why? Why did you come to my rescue?
なぜだ？
なぜ お前は助けに来た？
お前にとって 私は邪魔者なはず
In your eyes, I'm a hindrance. As is Lady Amira, I assume.
恐らく アーミラ嬢も…
And yet...
なのに ファバロ
Just who are you really, Favaro?
お前は何なのだ？
Ain't it obvious?
（ファバロ）
決まってんだろ
I'm me.
俺は俺だ
A nefarious, lying, backstabbing villain, right?
裏切り者の大うそつきの極悪人…
だろ？
Yes.
Exactly right!
そうだとも！
You're a big-headed, loose-lipped womanizer!
（カイザル）
お調子者で
口が軽くて
女にだらしがない！
That's why I say you're so
narrow-minded, Hammer Head!
（ファバロ）
だから お前は
視野が狭いってんだよ
ハンマーヘッド！
Silence, Bomber Head!
だまれ！　ボンバーヘッド！
（ファバロ）
ぶへあ！
（カイザル）
ぬはあ！
This isn't the time for fun and games.
（リタ）
遊んでる場合じゃないわよ
She's disappeared from her room.
あのお子様
部屋からいなくなったわ
Seriously?!
（ファバロ）
マジか…
This way, Amira.
（男）
こっちだ アーミラ
たく… 世話の焼ける女だぜ
Man, she's such a high-maintenance girl.
What is this place, anyway?
つ～か ここ どこだ？
That's...
これは…
あの夢で見たのと同じ…
That's the thing from my dreams!
What are you doing here?
（ジャンヌ）
ここで何をしている？
Jeanne! Jeanne D'Arc!
（ファバロ）
ジャンヌ！
ジャンヌ･ダルク…
Of all the people to run into, it just had to be her!
こりゃ また
とんでもねえのと出くわしちまった
Oh, just taking a walk to clear my head!
（ファバロ）
あ～ 酔い覚ましの散歩です
Well, see ya!
そんじゃ
気になるか？　バハムートが
Are you curious about Bahamut?
What did you just say?
今 何て…
Bahamut, the destroyer-to-be of our world.
バハムート
世界に滅亡をもたらすもの
A creature that is neither god nor demon and whose power surpasses all.
神にも悪魔にも属さず
何者をも超越する怪物
It is said that all lands will be reduced to nothingness once its power awakens.
その力が ひとたび目覚めれば
全ての大地は無に帰るという
That's Bahamut?
こいつが バハムート…
はるか昔のことだ
It happened long, long ago.
突如 空から現れたバハムートは
Bahamut suddenly appeared from the skies
and turned the world into a living hell in the blink of an eye.
またたく間に
世界を地獄へと塗り替えた
The land was enveloped in fire.
Nearly all life was mercilessly wiped out.
大地は炎に包まれ
あらゆる者が
無残に死に絶えていった
But just when gods, demons, and humans alike had abandoned all hope...
神も悪魔も人間も絶望した
そのとき
a miracle happened.
奇跡が起きた
The Supreme God Zeus transformed himself into the "God Key"
最高神ゼウスは“神の鍵”
and the Demon Lord Satan transformed himself into the "Demon Key."
魔王サタンは
“悪魔の鍵”に姿を変え
At the risk of their lives, they were also able to seal Bahamut in Abos.
その身を挺(てい)して
バハムートをエイボスに封じ込めた
This stone statue is modeled after it.
これは その姿を模した石像
The people visit it to offer their prayers and achieve inner peace.
人々は この像の前で祈りをささげ
心の平穏を得るのだ
They pray to a monster?
（ファバロ）
怪物に祈りを？
No, they pray...
いや 祈りの対象は…
to that.
あれだ
A holy knight, prophesied by the gods.
神々が予言した聖なる騎士
Prophesied?
（ファバロ）
予言？
When Bahamut revives, a knight will appear and bring peace to the land.
（ジャンヌ）
バハムートが復活せしとき
１人の騎士が現れ
地上に平和をもたらす…
The citizens of the Royal Capital believe in this prophecy,
この予言を王都の民は信じている
and they believe that I am that holy knight.
そして
私こそが その聖なる騎士なのだと
I, too, earnestly hope to be that
holy knight, should the time ever come.
仮に そのときが来たならば
私自身も
そうありたいと強く願っている
So it's got nothin' to do with me, then.
（ファバロ）
俺には関係ない話だな
What makes you think that?
（ジャンヌ）
なぜ そう思う？
I wound up coming here 'cause I got involved with a weird demon girl,
ヘンテコな悪魔女に
関わったばかりに
ここへ来るはめになっちまったが
but booze, girls, and freedom are all I really need.
本来 俺は
日々の酒と女と自由があれば
I'm just a plain old bounty hunter.
それで十分な ただの賞金稼ぎだ
World ruin and knights of prophecy and all that got nothing to do with me.
世界の破滅だの予言の騎士だの
別世界の話さ
I wouldn't be so sure.
（ジャンヌ）
果たして そうかな？
Huh?
I was originally just a simple
farm girl from a remote village.
（ジャンヌ）
私も元は
辺境の村に生まれた平凡な農民だ
Even so, I received the light and revelation of the gods and was awakened to my mission.
しかし それでも
神の啓示を受け
己の使命に目覚めた
Everyone is born for a reason.
Everyone is born to play a role.
人には それぞれ生まれた意味
背負った役割がある
きっと お前にもあるはずだ
I'm certain the same is true for you.
You were destined to meet the key girl for a reason.
あの鍵の娘と出会った
その理由がな
A reason?
理由？
Get real.
そんなもん…
あるわけねえだろ
There is no reason.
Who are you?
あなた 誰？
なぜ 同じペンダント…
Why do you have the same pendant?
I was asked to hold onto it by your mother.
（男）
預かったのだ　お前の母から
My mother?
お母さんから？
もしかして…
Does this mean...
You're...
あなたは…
お前にだって いんだろ？　父親
You have a father too, dontcha?!
My destiny,
sotto oshiete hoshii
won't you tell me?
aenai
But you're gone
ima wa tooi place to be
in a place so far away
unmei wa kawaru to
"Fate changes"
oshietekureta the truth is free
That's what you told me, and now the truth is free
I miss you
I revere you
You're my everything
I will follow you
subete wa ano toki
It all began then
To the promised land
tsuretette
So take me
yakusoku no basho e
to the promised land
More demons?!
また 魔族かよ！
（アザゼル）
人間ども
Playtime is over now, humans.
今度は お遊びなしだ
（ファバロ）
趣味は機械工作
時計付きの剣は俺の名作だ！
Life is a series of close calls!
Huh?
These previews are a perfect example!
（カイザル）
その時計 壊れてる
（ファバロ）
うるせえ！
じゃあ お前の趣味は？
I don't agree!
Then try reading with me!
（カイザル）私は…
（ファバロ）ああ もう！
On the next Rage of Bahamut: Genesis, "Roundup"!
（ファバロ）
次回「神撃(しんげき)のバハムート GENESIS(ジェネシス)」
The(ザ) Storm(ストーム) Rages(レイジズ)
See?
（カイザル）
鶏肉が好きです！
Roundup...
Illustration:
Next week, let's Bahamut...
...to the max.